{
    "id": "e63aa71d642a4b56b78b54313671d49d",
    "title": "Present Perfect Or Present Perfect Continuous Tense Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "cf1fadd7fa8747528cc56143daff2e92",
            "title": "Present Perfect Or Present Perfect Continuous Tense Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "How long ........................ Julie?",
                    "description": "Some verbs are not normally used in the continuous form. Know is one of them. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have you known",
                        "have you been knowing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ............................. all morning. I am tired.",
                    "description": "We use the perfect continuous when the focus is on the continuity rather than the completion. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have worked",
                        "have been working",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ........................ ten letters since morning.",
                    "description": "Here the emphasis is on the idea of completion and hence we use the perfect tense. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "wrote",
                        "have written",
                        "have been writing"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I have already ......................... the report.",
                    "description": "Here we are talking about a finished action and hence we use the perfect tense. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "received",
                        "been receiving",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "Sorry about the mess. We ...................... the walls.",
                    "description": "Here we are talking about an ongoing situation and therefore we use the present perfect continuous tense. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have painted",
                        "have been painting",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "This is the fifth time you .......................... that question.",
                    "description": "We use the present perfect in structures with 'this is the first/second/third time...'",
                    "answers": [
                        "asked",
                        "have asked",
                        "have been asking"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You ...................... a dozen cookies today.",
                    "description": "Here again the emphasis is on the idea of completion. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have eaten",
                        "have been eating",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "We ............................. in this city for ten years.",
                    "description": "The present perfect and the present perfect continuous can both be used to talk about actions and situations that started in the past and have continued up to the present. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have lived",
                        "have been living",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "John ........................... his leg so he can't walk.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "has broken",
                        "has been breaking",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "You look hot. What ............................ ?",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "have you done",
                        "have you been doing",
                        "did you do"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Help! I ......................... my purse.",
                    "description": "We are talking about a finished action here and hence we use the present perfect. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have lost",
                        "have been losing",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "'You look tired.' 'Yes, I .............................'",
                    "description": "The present perfect continuous can be used to talk about situations that have just stopped and have present results. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "have run",
                        "have been running",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}